<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>notes.u2on</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>u2on</name>
        <email>me@notu.dev</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>notes @ 10.04.2022</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/stmw-10-04.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/stmw-10-04.html</id>
    <published>2022-10-04</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 10.04.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        
      
      
        | [complete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <p><strong>The Adventures of Sayf Ben Dhi Yazan</strong></p>
<p>Written during a very consequential and interesting period of history</p>
<h2 id="epic">Epic</h2>
<p>Lengthy narrative, involving a time beyond living memory in which occured the extraordinary actions of exceptional humans (<strong>Not Gods</strong>) which often involve the supernatural.</p>
<h2 id="characters">Characters</h2>
<p><strong>Sayf Ben Dhi Yazan</strong> - (Sayf, son of Dhi Yazan) - Protaganist - Based on 6th century CE Yemeni king of Jewish Himyarite Dynasty - Repelled the Askumite invasions from Ethiopia</p>
<p><strong>Sayf Ar’ed</strong> - Arch-enemy of Sayf Ben Dhi Yazan - Based on 14th century CE Christian Ethiopian king - Fought against Muslim expansion in the Horn of Africa</p>
<h2 id="setting">Setting</h2>
<p>(Tangentially Related) Islands of Waq’Waq (European spelling: Wak’Wak) Written in the end of the “medivial ages” in Egypt - Northern Egypt (all the way to Modern-Day Syria) Ruled by Mamluke (or Mamluk). Mongol invasion of Egypt -&gt; Bigger than a Kingdom, Smaller than an Empire. Mamluk were Balkan (millitary) slaves of the Ottomans, would be freed on merit (e.g. high enough promotion), then ruled themselves.</p>
<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>Four centuries of war and power struggles in the Horn of Africa - Crusades (1095 - 1291) - 4 to 5 Crusades - Attemt to Control Jerusalem - Polticially related to split in Church - 1050 -&gt; Split between Chatholic Church and Eastern Orthodox Church - Undertones of Material+Economical pillage - Mongol Invasions (1207 - …) - Baghdad Falls (1258) - Huge series of battles between Mongols and Mamluk (~1278)</p>
<h2 id="context-of-conflict">Context of Conflict</h2>
<p>The Adventures of Sayf Ben Dhi Yazan is about war - An innate desire for the documentation of the conflict under the guise of fantasy. - Reassurance of the security of the Umma(h). - Emphisis on Sayf Ben Dhi Yazan’s sympathy and mercy assauges the underlying disgust with killing - Aknowledges it as a necessary part of existance</p>
<h2 id="problems-presented-in-the-book">Problems presented in the book</h2>
<ul>
<li>The ‘pagan’/‘infidel’
<ul>
<li>Impact of conversion</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Race
<ul>
<li>Curse of Noah</li>
<li>Opposites
<ul>
<li>White is only white in comparison to Black, and vice versa</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Women and power
<ul>
<li>Can women rule?</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>achieving vanilla suckless scroll functionality</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/vsf.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/vsf.html</id>
    <published>2022-09-02</published>
    <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 09.02.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/config.html">config</a>
      
      
        | [complete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h3 id="background">background</h3>
<p>For the last ~2 years, as I’ve been migrating my workflow to align with the ‘less is more’ mantra. One issue I’ve encountered is inherent to this methodology; less, is well, less. Stripping unnecessary features and making opt-in the expectation is the ‘correct’ solution. But common agreement on how to re-implement opt-in functionality is paramount to the installation<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a> of these tools.</p>
<h3 id="solutions">solution(s)</h3>
<p>The only time that I <strong>need</strong> scrolling in my terminal emulator is when inspecting make/gcc build output. Every other tool has scroll functionality encompassed within; vim, gdb, man, etc. Patching this into ST is unnecessary<a href="#fn2" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref2" role="doc-noteref"><sup>2</sup></a>; given that I don’t need this functionality for any other tool. A simple solution is to alias <code>vmake</code> (verbose make) to a <code>less</code> command pipe; <code>alias vmake='less &lt; &lt;(make 2&gt;&amp;1)'</code><a href="#fn3" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref3" role="doc-noteref"><sup>3</sup></a>.</p>
<p>We can expand this functionality to non-default <code>make</code> commands with UNIX style piping; simply alias <code>'less&lt; &lt;($0 2&gt;&amp;1)'</code> as appropriate. <strong>Most commands can be piped to <code>less</code> natively</strong>; <code>make</code> was the outlier. It would initially output correctly, but then it (or <code>less</code>, I’m not sure) would wipe the output.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>I view Suckless tools as a minimalist interpretation of the original UNIX philosophy. Because of this, once you set them up, you’re unlikely to be forced to modify it due to breakage.<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2" role="doc-endnote"><p>While Suckless’ scroll is a valiant effort, it’s run into some <a href="https://tools.suckless.org/scroll/">non-negotiable problems</a><a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3" role="doc-endnote"><p>Found this pipe syntax after doing a deep forum dive; <a href="https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/programming-9/how-to-pipe-output-from-make-325285/">original source</a><a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Influence and Magic</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/infmag.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/infmag.html</id>
    <published>2022-06-16</published>
    <updated>2022-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 06.16.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/theory.html">theory</a>, <a href="/tags/religion.html">religion</a>, <a href="/tags/term%20paper.html">term paper</a>
      
      
        | [complete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h3 id="forward">Forward</h3>
<p>This is a term paper I wrote for my Honors Exposition and Argument class last year. Provided are the two papers which were used as reference. <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2007/02/the-ecstasy-of-influence/">Letham’s The Ecstasy of Influence</a> &amp; <a href="https://online.ucpress.edu/nr/article/23/4/15/107331/The-Magical-Theory-of-PoliticsMemes-Magic-and-the">Asperm’s The Magical Theory of Politics</a>.</p>
<p>The prompt eludes me, but it seems to the effect of “How did meme magicians and 4chan use the commons?” (enlightening, I know)</p>
<h3 id="paper">Paper</h3>
<p>The creation of online memes is commonly seen as an inconsequential act, but once a malicious motivation is introduced, popularity becomes a large-scale propaganda operation to subtly influence the meme’s audience. Artists and ‘meme magicians’ share in their purpose of creation; both seek to impart their views on the world. The methodology and motivation, however, varies between the two. Letham writes in <em>The Ecstasy of Influence</em> a critique of the commercialization of the commons and analysis of the nature of ownership in art. Asprem, in <em>The Magical Theory of Politics</em>, discusses the use of memes and magic in the run up to the 2016 US presidential election. While artists are personal in their motivation, meme magicians are motivated by a divine will to subtly impose their views on others. Artists derive the commons to create novel content, while meme magicians utilize the commons to propagate malicious ideology through derivative, mutative content.</p>
<p>The commons, as referred to in Lethems’ piece, encompass the collective knowledge and existence of a culture. In its most basic sense, Lethem presents the commons through an analogy of a king and a cat; “The world that meets our eye through the lens of a camera was judged to be, with minor exceptions, a sort of public commons, where a cat may look at a king.” (Letham, pg. 236). The king may own his clothes, jewelry, etc, but the cat possesses the image of the king and his clothes, and as an intangible concept, it cannot be taken, sold, or otherwise owned. This perception of the commons as the world that surrounds us, and our perception of it, takes new meaning with the addition of Actor-Network Theory presented in Asprem’s work, wherein the role and nature of reality is impacted by actors within the aforementioned reality; “… chains of emotion linked through bodies, memes, ideas, and verbal statements take on an agency of their own; they are not only mobilized by people reacting instinctively to what which grabs their affective attention in the moment, but precisely because of the snowballing of spontaneous linkages …” (Asprem, pg. 35). Asprem refers to this reciprocal relationship between unique agents as ‘affective networking’, and argues that changes propagated through it affect the nature of those participating in it. The commons, as a mixture of collective knowledge and a distributed reality, serves to store a society’s conscious and unconscious knowledge.</p>
<p>The significance of unrelated events within an affective network can become distorted by the overall sentiment or bias of the network. Asprem’s meme magicians have a tendency to mystify and connect real world events with that of internet subculture. This hyperactive pattern recognition between the physical and virtual realities results in ‘magic memes’; causal links between physical events, such as a tragic plane crash in the alps; “… Germanwings Flight 9525 … crashed on 24 March 2015 when the suicidal co-pilot Andreas Lubitz deliberately steered the plane into a peak in the … French Alps, killing all 150 passengers” (Asprem, pg. 25), to fictional events being widely shared in the virtual network at roughly the same time; “Youtubers and 8chan users recognized a similarity between the event and the opening scene of the Batman movie … in which supervillain Bane downs a plane from the inside and escapes” (Asprem, pg. 25). The causal links are a symptom and cause of a recursive ecosystem. Weak links are supplemented with ironic belief and the existence of stronger links, which would later introduce the slippery slope of post-irony. The tendency of the meme magicians’ affective network to find or manufacture significance to support their ideology would eventually result in the deification of this hyperactive pattern recognition.</p>
<p>Rarified events within an affective network mutate the overall sentiment of the network via realized significance. Some events just have incredible odds, and in these circumstances, there is no need to manufacture significance. Unique tagging of messages is central to the 4chan boards, and long sequences of identical numbers are seen as a minor event, referred to as a ‘GET’. Asprem provides an example of one such ‘prophetic’ message; “… a post on 4chan’s /p/ board with the text “Trump will win” achieved the remarkable GET 77777777.” (Asprem, pg. 24). The disbelief that such an event would occur naturally introduces the possibility to the community that there exists a power possible of influencing reality, both virtual and physical. In Asprem’s paper, the imageboard inhabitants personified this deity into ‘Kek’, which itself was an amalgamation and mutation of the commons; the image was derived of a popular frog meme, Pepe, while the name was of an Egyptian deity of primordial darkness, who in greek depiction was presented as a frog headed man. This post-ironic acknowledgement of a malevolent source and an assigned motive of chaos gave new weight to the causal links and rarified events. Any subsequent events were seen as a reinforcement of the deity’s legitimacy and power. The slippery slope of ironic engagement to post-ironic justification enabled religious belief of a manifest power which could actualize change to further the interests of the affective network.</p>
<p>Artists derive from the commons and their own interpretation to produce novel content. Artists, as referenced by Letham’s work, create out of a need to impart the self on the many; “For so many artists, the act of creativity is intended as a Napoleonic imposition of one’s uniqueness upon the universe …” (Letham, pg. 24). While most art has parts derived from the commons, the aim of most artists is to create something unique to establish legacy and attach recognition to their name. Letham provides examples of artists seeking to create something unique, but their final work having portions of it directly or indirectly influenced, regardless of stated intent, by previous work or concepts; this is referred to as ‘cryptomnesia’. “Dylan’s art offers a paradox: while it famously urges us not to look back, it also encodes a knowledge of past sources that might otherwise have little home in contemporary culture … Dylan’s originality and his appropriations are as one.” (Letham, pg. 233). Bob Dylan’s work, referenced in this example, has a characteristic theme of “not looking back”, which Letham uses as a metaphor for artists’ paradoxical use of the commons with the intention of novelty. Of course it’s possible to create something unique, but is it possible to create something new? The commons thus provides a set of reference material for artists; it could be argued that the artists are less creators and more so linkers (which is creation in its own right, and another paradox), but this is beyond the scope of this paper. Artists manipulate and draw from the commons to create significance with others, linking themselves and others to ideas; making the world bigger. Artists inhabit a similar existence to meme magicians through the commons, which in itself acts as a sort of an affective-network; “The closest resemblance [to art] is to the commons of a language: altered by every contributor, expanded by even the most passive user” (Letham, pg. 244). The linking furthering the network’s propagation is between the self and the masses, rather than the physical and virtual.</p>
<p>Meme magicians derive the commons, mutate, and link their contents to support and propagate their ideology to the masses to impart actual impact. In Asprem’s work, the meme magicians are the imageboard users who utilized memes, through the commons, to share divisive views, including hate speech, to a wider internet audience in the lead up to the 2016 presidential election. The ‘magic’ portion of the terms refers to the “… Hyperactive pattern recognition in the context of high-speed posting …” on the image boards, “… giving rise to synchro-nistic meanings connecting memes posted on the imageboards to events in the external world.” (Apsrem, pg. 25). The meme magician’s ideology is under the guise of post-irony; ironic participation becomes unironic identification. Post-irony provides a layer of plausible deniability, allowing a prepretuator to claim ironic participation while simultaneously beginning to believe in the ideology. Post-ironic posting became a cornerstone of the methodology used by Asprem’s meme magicians, akin to the rationale behind their use of the commons; allowing divisive commentary to spread among innocuous media to the greater public, indoctrinating more people. Hostile takeover of the commons; most clearly demonstrated in the hijacking of a frog meme, demonstrates this; “In 2016, a group of users on the 4chan /pol/board (/pol/ standing for “politically incorrect,” … attempted to hijack Pepe by systematically producing memes that associated the frog with extreme-right views … and plastering these memes all over the internet.” (Asprem, pg. 23). Pepe was a non-political meme used by the internet community as an anthropomorphism of themselves; the 4chan campaign attempted, successfully, to change the way people thought about a very popular image, and all the images containing it. The mutation of an innocuous meme into a signal for far-right ideology represents the hostile use of the commons.</p>
<p>Is the nature of the commons binary? Can there be ‘good’ and ‘bad’ content in the context of an affective network? Creation, even when derived from mutation, can be seen as a growth of the commons whose value is subjective. Take the example of Van Goh, whose genius was only realised after his death. In no way am I equating the masterful art of Van Goh to images of frogs on the internet encoding hate speech, but Van Goh’s work does highlight the unstable nature of public sentiment regarding the commons. Fundamentally, the meme magicians simply link between rarified events in their virtual and physical worlds to propagate hateful ideology. But it is at what point this linking becomes its own form of creation that the line between artists and meme magicians begins to blur. Artists as described in Lethem’s work are individuals; many have their own demons and own prejudices. The designation of an artist and a crude artist; eg. meme magician, more so relies on the value of which their content evokes in the society. Banksy transformed from a crude artist; a graffiti tagger, to a world renown artist based solely on public opinion in the merit of his work. Within the imageboard from which they began, Asprem’s meme magicians are surely seen as artists; the hijacking of Pepe is viewed less of a hostile takeover of the commons and more a creative reimagination of which to identify with. Artists’ and meme magicians’ respective content represent two sides to the commons, but the distinction between the two is dependent on public perception.</p>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>helpful concord blobs</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/helpOC.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/helpOC.html</id>
    <published>2022-05-28</published>
    <updated>2022-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 05.28.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/code.html">code</a>
      
      
        | [incomplete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <p>This note contains some helpful scripts I’ve ended using over and over while creating things derived of the OC libraries. You may find them immediately useful, and if not, I hope you can take away the broader concepts present.</p>
<h4 id="copying-and-including-oc-libraries">Copying and Including OC Libraries</h4>
<p>Simple Makefile for moving existing git clones of Concord libraries to the necessary <code>lib/</code> folder. This isn’t necessary for standard global <code>/usr/</code> installs, but is for nightly build testing or for strictly local installs.</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1"><pre class="sourceCode makefile"><code class="sourceCode makefile"><span id="cb1-1"><a href="#cb1-1"></a><span class="dt">LK </span><span class="ch">=</span><span class="st"> -lcryptopp -lpthread -L./lib/core/</span></span>
<span id="cb1-2"><a href="#cb1-2"></a><span class="dt">CR </span><span class="ch">=</span><span class="st"> -I./lib/core/inc</span></span>
<span id="cb1-3"><a href="#cb1-3"></a><span class="dt">UT </span><span class="ch">=</span><span class="st"> -I./lib/uttu/inc</span></span>
<span id="cb1-4"><a href="#cb1-4"></a></span>
<span id="cb1-5"><a href="#cb1-5"></a><span class="co"># Change to appropriate dir or pass as input through shell script</span></span>
<span id="cb1-6"><a href="#cb1-6"></a><span class="dt">LC </span><span class="ch">=</span><span class="st"> ~/code/concord/core/src/</span></span>
<span id="cb1-7"><a href="#cb1-7"></a><span class="dt">LU </span><span class="ch">=</span><span class="st"> ~/code/concord/uttu/</span></span>
<span id="cb1-8"><a href="#cb1-8"></a></span>
<span id="cb1-9"><a href="#cb1-9"></a>...</span>
<span id="cb1-10"><a href="#cb1-10"></a></span>
<span id="cb1-11"><a href="#cb1-11"></a><span class="co"># go into local version of core &amp; uttu, build, and then cp to ./lib/</span></span>
<span id="cb1-12"><a href="#cb1-12"></a><span class="co"># -- core needs uttu</span></span>
<span id="cb1-13"><a href="#cb1-13"></a><span class="dv">reset:</span></span>
<span id="cb1-14"><a href="#cb1-14"></a>	cd <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">LU</span><span class="ch">)</span> &amp;&amp; <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">MAKE</span><span class="ch">)</span> clean &amp;&amp; <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">MAKE</span><span class="ch">)</span> linux_obj</span>
<span id="cb1-15"><a href="#cb1-15"></a>	cp -r <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">LU</span><span class="ch">)</span>build/exe/. ./lib/uttu/</span>
<span id="cb1-16"><a href="#cb1-16"></a>	cp -r lib/uttu <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">LC</span><span class="ch">)</span>../lib/</span>
<span id="cb1-17"><a href="#cb1-17"></a>	cd <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">LC</span><span class="ch">)</span> &amp;&amp; <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">MAKE</span><span class="ch">)</span> clean &amp;&amp; <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">MAKE</span><span class="ch">)</span></span>
<span id="cb1-18"><a href="#cb1-18"></a>	cp -r <span class="ch">$(</span><span class="dt">LC</span><span class="ch">)</span>../exe/. ./lib/core</span></code></pre></div>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>ensuring fair trade in user generated content</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/fairtrade.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/fairtrade.html</id>
    <published>2022-04-26</published>
    <updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 04.26.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/math.html">math</a>, <a href="/tags/game%20theory.html">game theory</a>
      
      
        | [incomplete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h3 id="preamble">Preamble</h3>
<p>I propose a system of governance for user-created content in online games; mimicking zero trust design schemes to: maintain appropriate sustainability, and avoid hyperinflation of in-game markets or currency. This proposal largely focuses on MMOs as a base, given the massive need for new engaging content, the existence of player-to-player economy, and a large player base.</p>
<h3 id="burden-of-cost">Burden of Cost</h3>
<p>The eventual degradation of a “good”<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a> online game is seldom the lack of active players. It is, instead, the burden of cost on the publisher; maintenance of servers, new content, and other costs of doing business. Ideally, these games should be open sourced at the end of this lifecycle, left in a state similar to gmod<a href="#fn2" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref2" role="doc-noteref"><sup>2</sup></a>. Some success stories include OpenTTD<a href="#fn3" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref3" role="doc-noteref"><sup>3</sup></a>, where the player base becomes the developer of the game, releasing (economic) burden from the publisher and/or game studio.</p>
<p>While the eventual release of game IP into the commons is a controversial opinion to say the least, at lease these issues can be solved by the introduction of fair trade systems into community content. In this context, fair trade is not the arrangement designed to directly connect farmers to consumers, but is instead a system designed to have accurate and appropriate risk<span class="math inline">\(:\)</span>reward ratio.</p>
<h3 id="small-steps">Small Steps</h3>
<p>Let’s start with a small game concept.</p>
<p>Our super cool new mobile MMO 4x game is called <em>Super Interdimensional Galactic Defense Force</em>. Players control an initially small colony, that generates capital and money by exploring surrounding terrain and collecting resources. The planet on which our game takes place is also inhabited by a dangerous race of apex predators. They’ve inflicted heavy losses on all of our foraging parties, and so any research on their weaknesses would greatly aid in our development of effective personal protection units.</p>
<p>Without doing too much subrate world building, let’s assume that there is a nonzero count of corporations who pay handsomely for body parts from these aliens; to gain an advantage in their research.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We’ve introduced a ambiguous but valid threat, a justification for compensation, and almost limitless creative liberty. Besides lore considerations, the limiting factor is now the actual content.<a href="#fn4" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref4" role="doc-noteref"><sup>4</sup></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>We assume a game environment is composed of a set of dimensionally equal tiles, which each have the ability to contain <span class="math inline">\(\le{1}\)</span> copies of a unique asset<a href="#fn5" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref5" role="doc-noteref"><sup>5</sup></a>. We also assume all possible assets are known, and for the sake of sanity, assign them to set <span class="math inline">\(A\)</span>.</p>
<h3 id="game-loop-nuance">Game Loop Nuance</h3>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>A game that does not suffer from long term player loss due to lack of content.<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2" role="doc-endnote"><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garry%27s_Mod">Garry’s Mod</a> has extensive documentation for both modding and server maintenance, requiring almost complete hands-off support from Valve.<a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3" role="doc-endnote"><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenTTD">Open Transport Tycoon Deluxe</a> is a open source fan remake of the popular TransportTycoonDeluxe, and is incredibly successful and well reviewed on steam.<a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn4" role="doc-endnote"><p>Although, this scenario has enough ambiguity that any lore-breaking additions can be shuffled (admittedly lazily) into any one of the gimmicky “this doesn’t count but counts” modifiers; interdimensional leak, time jumping, genetic mutation with a shady catalyst, etc.<a href="#fnref4" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn5" role="doc-endnote"><p>This allows us to have partial portions of assets, allowing for say a 4 tile large building.<a href="#fnref5" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>headaches w/ gravity</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/grav.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/grav.html</id>
    <published>2022-04-14</published>
    <updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 04.14.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/math.html">math</a>, <a href="/tags/physics.html">physics</a>, <a href="/tags/astro.html">astro</a>
      
      
        | [incomplete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h3 id="section-list">Section List</h3>
<ul>
<li>overview &amp; necessary disclaimer</li>
<li>degredation of accuracy and acceptable degrees
<ul>
<li>interactions of the 3D</li>
<li>physical interactions between bodies</li>
<li>acceptable degrees of error</li>
</ul></li>
<li>time as an influence
<ul>
<li>time as a meter</li>
<li>4d in its interactions with the aforementioned 3d system</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="overview">Overview</h3>
<p>In the pursuit of a <span class="math inline">\(\underline{\text{workable}}\)</span> platform to simulate an approximate universe, obviously a very large endeavor, I seek to understand and condense the interactions between bodies in space, and formulate it to a set of functions and variables to represent any encounter between two bodies in space. Actually <em>accurately</em> simulating the entire universe is a foolish task. This is mainly presented as a thought exercise.</p>
<h3 id="degradation-of-accuracy-and-acceptable-degrees">Degradation of Accuracy and Acceptable Degrees</h3>
<p><strong>… in a simulated system</strong></p>
<p>All bodies of some mass have impact on the movements of the others. While discounting this below a certain threshold might serve to reduce the overall complexity of the calculus; e.g. <span class="math display">\[F_x : \{(F_x\prec b) \nless \lfloor b_z - t\rfloor \}\]</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Where <span class="math inline">\(x\)</span> is measure of influence<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a>, <span class="math inline">\(t\)</span> is some threshold, <span class="math inline">\(z\)</span> is relative gravitational force (in this context of <span class="math inline">\(b\)</span>) taken at constant distance, and <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> is a set of all influential <span class="math inline">\(b\)</span>, <span class="math inline">\(\forall\)</span> bodies <span class="math inline">\(b\)</span> of <span class="math inline">\(B\)</span>. It is implied that <span class="math inline">\(F_x \subset B\)</span>.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><em>While I take the influence as a floored number (assumed at <span class="math inline">\(10^0\)</span>), any variation (the one I primarily consider is <span class="math inline">\(\lfloor ... \rceil\)</span>) suffices; as long as it is constant across <span class="math inline">\(x\)</span>.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This necessary exclusion of bodies would eventually create a slip in accuracy beyond the (acceptable) marginal degree. Another flaw is the inclusion of equal values of <span class="math inline">\(x\)</span> for <span class="math inline">\(F_x \prec b\)</span> and <span class="math inline">\(b_x\)</span>; it may create a plateau of <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span>, and given <span class="math inline">\(\forall \space x \mid x \space \notin F_x\)</span>, a stable relational system<a href="#fn2" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref2" role="doc-noteref"><sup>2</sup></a>. This is bad because it’s boring.</p>
<table style="width:6%;">
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 6%" />
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>We can attempt to create a buffer set between all bodies <span class="math inline">\(b\)</span> and what we’d consider influential bodies <span class="math inline">\(F_x(b)\)</span>.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Create a set <span class="math inline">\(N_x\)</span> (null <span class="math inline">\(x\)</span>), and take the greatest of that set, and then push it up to <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span>. <span class="math display">\[e : N_x \begin{cases} e \notin F_x\\ e \exists! \in N_x \\e \top\{N_x\} \end{cases}\]</span> <span class="math display">\[ N_x = (N_x - e)\]</span> <span class="math display">\[ e \to F_x \]</span></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>This just pushes the slip in accuracy one level down; there’s now a slip of threshold in each calculation: given that the threshold is being set and then ignored for one body each iteration, as <span class="math inline">\(|N_x|\)</span> decreases, so does the legitimacy of the threshold - for enough bodies that have been excluded, <span class="math inline">\(N_x = \emptyset\)</span>. This could be solved by setting a hard limit on how many former <span class="math inline">\(N_x\)</span> bodies can populate <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span>, but then you may as well just lower the threshold enough to consider those bodies in <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> originally.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>It may make sense to impose some sense of <em>inherited</em> order on the actual count of bodies in the <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> set, but that would, like the set of <span class="math inline">\(N_x\)</span>, only push the slip further down, rather than solve it. Almost all solutions have this slip, and hence we must account for the degradation of accuracy, and the acceptable degrees of error.</p>
<p>One solution I’m considering is the creation of zones of attraction between sets of <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span>. Creating a sorted 3 dimensional vector of all sets of <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> could enable the pseudo sorting of these zone of attraction without actually attaching any explicit tag to each set.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But wait, that’s just what everyone else does.<a href="#fn3" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref3" role="doc-noteref"><sup>3</sup></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ensuring sane degrees of accuracy necessitates consideration of appropriate scope; if at great enough distance that <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> begins to exclude bodies and thus create <span class="math inline">\(N_x\)</span>, the entire gravitation force of <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> becomes monolithic (when considered against other bodies (including other <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span>)). One way to retain the ‘naturality’ of the generation of <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> would be the connection of <span class="math inline">\(t\)</span> to something related to the count of objects in <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> or maybe the index in the 3 dimensional vector. (I’m still not sure)</p>
<hr />
<p>This is the problem with binary generation of ‘valid’ bodies; the necessary exclusion of other bodies creates either a slip in the criteria (see above), or a series of monolithic gravitational zones that operate mainly as closed systems. Unfortunately, from my very small amount of research on the subject, it seems the latter is the more realistic scenario.</p>
<p>This does mean most of the fun is sucked out of the exercise, but at least the micro of how exactly to interact smaller bodies (or particles, if we’re literally micro) within these monolithic zones of influence. Oh, and we can spice things up with time.</p>
<h5 id="time-as-an-influence">Time as an Influence</h5>
<p><strong>…(and Willing Participant)</strong></p>
<p>Given that Einsteinian physics is a cooler system<a href="#fn4" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref4" role="doc-noteref"><sup>4</sup></a>, time is going to be considered with this simulation. To help myself visualize the 4th dimension, and to succinctly explain my rationale, a <em>simple</em> metaphor will be used<a href="#fn5" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref5" role="doc-noteref"><sup>5</sup></a>. Imagine, if you will, the 4th dimension as a photo camera. A still frame is taken of the 3rd dimension<a href="#fn6" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref6" role="doc-noteref"><sup>6</sup></a>; these images, overlaid in order, become a body’s experience of the 4th dimension. Time, in this system, exists as the frame-rate of the camera; the closer to light speed a body is, the slower its relative time. In our metaphor, this would be represented as the gaps between each frame.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>This can also be considered the index of any <span class="math inline">\(b\)</span>; given that <span class="math inline">\(F_x\)</span> is sorted.<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2" role="doc-endnote"><p>This is a little misleading; if the relational force is the same across the entire system, nothing will ever move out of the <em>perfect</em> sequence in any substantial way without external force.<a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3" role="doc-endnote"><p><em>I don’t know that, but I assume that it’s the conclusion that others have also come to.</em><a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn4" role="doc-endnote"><p>(Source: Trust me bro)<a href="#fnref4" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn5" role="doc-endnote"><p>This disclaimer means you can’t yell at me on twitter. Acceptance of this wavier of your right to flame me online will be the continued reading of this footnote.<a href="#fnref5" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
<li id="fn6" role="doc-endnote"><p>Without the 4th dimension, the 3d dimension has no concept of time, so it kind of just exists without concrete, well, time. Taking a still requires the concept of time (via reflection), and so I consider this precis valid, while admittedly marginally confusing.<a href="#fnref6" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>creating a tiny big number library</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/tbn.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/tbn.html</id>
    <published>2022-03-24</published>
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 03.24.2022
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        <a href="/tags/math.html">math</a>
      
      
        | [incomplete]
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h4 id="tiny-big-number-lib---background">Tiny Big Number Lib - Background</h4>
<p>Tiny Big Number Lib was written so that I could do physics projects and other large simulations in C++ without a huge amount of dependency overhead. It aims to implement the <span class="math inline">\(\underline{\text{bare minimum}}\)</span> necessary to do these calculations.</p>
<h3 id="implementation-notes-design-decisions">Implementation Notes + Design Decisions</h3>
<h5 id="big-vs-signed_big">big vs signed_big</h5>
<p>While the initial methods were able to just used an aliased vector of unsigned integers; <code>using big = std::vector&lt;unsigned int&gt;;</code>, as soon as subtraction was being added, it made sense to implement some form of signing. As I’m doing my best to keep the library as ‘vanillia’ as possible, this was achieved by aliasing a tuple of a bool and a big to <code>signed_big</code>. A simple translation namespace was created; <code>unpack</code> for QoL. It may make sense later to form a standardised <code>struct</code> model, but for now this will suffice.</p>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>op/status</title>
    <link href="https://notu.dev/notes/posts/board.html" />
    <id>https://notu.dev/notes/posts/board.html</id>
    <published>2000-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2000-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<article>
    <section class="header">
        
          pub: 01.01.2000
        
    </section>
    <section class="info">
      
        
      
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <h1 id="updates">Updates</h1>
<p>Site is currently being built, sorry for any mess.</p>
    </section>
</article>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
