<rss version="0.92"><channel><title>txt://u2on</title><link>https://www.notu.dev/txt</link><description>Collected writings</description>
<item>
<title>Genology in Desolation</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/artic</link>
<pubDate>29/05/23</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Genology in DesolationEach specimen has been honed into the best iteration of their own local extrema, in both enivronment and genology.There is also something alluring about the challenge of desolation; it is the truest form of examination -- the highest stakes of nature. To lose is to fail the process of evolution, to win is both the sucession of the future genome, and the justification for its current iteration. Elegantly, desolation is the levelest playing field of evolution; it is the most barren and honest plain (+/plane) on which to judge life.Certainly, the overt complexity of more bountiful environments isn't a disqualification for their respective inhabitants; one can appreciate the lean, mean form of the cat as much as the streamlined elegance of the penguin. The deserts of the world are instead the most bare (barren) of all, and their inhabitants are nessecariliy the most effective, the most streamlined. Environmental complexity is much more naunced, and the number of inhabitants significantly reduced. This would lead one to beilive that this fascination is caused by the simplicity of evaluation -- it is much harder to comprehend why a jungle creature has evolved into its niche because of the complexity of its environment.---------------------Last Edited: 29/05/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Books should not be banned</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/books</link>
<pubDate>03/06/23</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Books should not be banned==========================The state of Florida has engaged in overtly Orwellian legislation which has provided a legal framework for citizens to outright ban books in schools[0].This is deeply troubling, but is unfortunately indicitive of a larger trend of proud stupidity.      Emotional thinking has become acceptable justifiaction for the parties of the United States. It justifies the loop of 'negative' voting[1], and provides the uneducated a base on which they feel comfortable. The uneducated will thus look to further reinforce their anchor of fear. The entirely draconian measure of banning books, which as excepted[2], is osetensibly done "for the children", is a means to an end. It substitutes reasonable discourse for emotional and personal opinion. The uneducated, having found a basis for their emotional opinions which they knowingly cannot justify sine rectus pretense, will attempt to restrict all other. Instead of having a constructive interpretation to challenges to their views, they emotionally react; drawing upon unchallengable pretense to justify their views; even substituting predicate logic as argument for pretense as argument. At which point, challenging their views is akin to challenging their pretenses, whether that be on religion, politics, or the nature of the universe. Only an one who is either an imbecile or malicous would do something so abhorrent.[0]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230527021136/https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/republican-2024-hopeful-ron-desantis-is-blazing-a-trail-on-school-book-bans>[1]: <https://www.notu.dev/txt/voting.txt>[2]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230602025041/https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Think_of_the_children>---------------------Last Edited: 03/06/23 ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Be wary of those who justify a diametric means to an end; often the end is but a mirage.</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/ends</link>
<pubDate>of</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Be wary of those who justify a diametric means to an end; often the end is but a mirage.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>When in a social setting...</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/int</link>
<pubDate>the</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[When in a social setting...When reviewing text...Always assume the best intentions, but never leave anything up to interpretation.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Markdown sucks</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/md</link>
<pubDate>06/06/23</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Markdown sucks==============Once, I was smitten with markdown -- it was an enhanced plaintext format; what wasn't to love? Very soon I realised that intrinsically, there is no functional difference between markdown and plaintext, except for presentation. And like many of the visual protocols, it fell to bloated standards.The issue is fundamentally one of control characters. Even the minimal amount of control characters intrinsically increases complexity; when you have an intermixed block of arbitrary text and control characters, the complexity is linear to the amount of control characters defined.Markdown has set a precedent for acceptance; this results in ambiguous standards where nearly all non-alphanumeric characters represent some portion of some control sequence. It is a significant pain to NOT accidentally transcribe a control character.At the risk of slightly lackluster presentation (the horror), plaintext is exactly what you intend it to be. With the addition of unicode, it's even possible to make plaintext flashy, but I've found that plain old ASCII is enough for me.Post Script===========> John Gruber’s canonical description of Markdown’s syntax does not specify the syntax unambiguously. [0]> Because there is no unambiguous spec, implementations have diverged considerably over the last 10 years. As a result, users are often surprised to find that a document that renders one way on one system (say, a GitHub wiki) renders differently on another (say, converting to docbook using Pandoc). To make matters worse, because nothing in Markdown counts as a “syntax error,” the divergence often isn’t discovered right away. [0]The grand experiment of intrepting plaintext as control sequences has resulted in ... ambiguity. Could anyone have forseen this?[0]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230603082515/https://commonmark.org/>---------------------Last Edited: 06/06/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Voting is important; not to 'win', but rather for the participation in the process.</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/voting</link>
<pubDate>28/05/23</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Voting is important; not to 'win', but rather for the participation in the process.===================================================================================Voting as honest participation in the process is 'positive' voting; that is, voting in favor of legistlation that you holistically agree with.Voting to stop the 'other side' from success is 'negative' voting; this generally includes intentionally deadlocking legislation or candidacy for office.</p>      Majoritarian electoral systems corrupt the meaning of voting through 2 major processes:1. The consolidation of voters2. The reinforcement of 'negative' votingThese form a series of run-off processes, which serve to further reinforce the two major processes.In no particular order:   a. The precipitation of policy and identity ambiguity  b. Legislative deadlock in systems with delayed terms  c. The loss of the moderates  d. The normalisation of advocacy for extreme policyBig parties formed via the consolidation of voters through 'negative' voting are incentivised to cater to the extremes of their general alignment. These extreme voters have no qualms about voting 'positively'; consequently, their voting patterns inspire the opposing moderates to vote 'negatively'. They thus form the crucial margin for large parties; they serve to keep the moderates in check, while providing the literal margin for election. Extreme policy is accordingly promoted to attract these extreme voters, and the moderates are relegated to an infinite loop of 'negative' voting.There will be growing pains as the moderates play an increasingly high-stakes game of chicken, but the only intra-process reform possible is enacted through voting 'positively'.-------------------Last Edit: 28/05/23 ]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>
