<rss version="0.92"><channel><title>txt://u2on</title><link>https://www.notu.dev/txt</link><description>Collected writings</description>
<item>
<title>Five Star Ratings are Functional</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/5star.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Five Star Ratings are Functional
================================

The ratio rating scheme counterintuitively provides an effective screen for technical competency. Assuming an honest rater (this is crucial), the ratio scheme forces underlying technical quality to be rated, rather than subjective taste.

At the risk of adage (of this entire file);
> Sally listens to a true crime podcast, tasteful murder. Sally finds the content too jovial, but ultimately assess it as not her cup of tea. Sally found nothing wrong with the hosts, the script, the sound design, or the concept. She's just ambivelent. Sally should rate the podcast ~4-5 stars for OK.

This the a general modus operandi of reviewers in ratio rating schemes. I suspect that it's almost entirely due to vote inflation[0], but it also provides a good technical screen; only the most abhorrent will be rated low.

[0]: 7 is the new 5

---------------------
Last Edited: 06/11/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Those attracted to alternative platforms</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/alt.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Those attracted to alternative platforms
========================================

My views regarding platforms has already been documented[0], but the people who are attracted to these alternative platforms are sometimes awful.

People who are banned off of major platforms are usually;
a) vocal
b) not fully ... lucid
c) aggressive

These major platforms aren't incentivised to kick off every person who may have a gripe with their existence; how would they make money? It's the truly disruptive and irreformable people who are forcibly removed. These people are bad for everything; bad for advertisers, bad for users (children to adults), and bad for the dynamic of the site. Only alternative platforms which have varying levels of acceptance (between impartial or welcoming) are suitable places for these transients.

I use odysee for my RSS feeds of channels, to avoid youtube when possible. The people who comment on that site are generally the most detached from reality that I've ever seen, even on certain infamous image boards. As a product of their existence, most of the 'special' commenters are a delightful blend of antisemitism, anti-vaxx, fascist, and insurrectionist.

People like this should just be left alone, or given some form of help. I just wish I didn't have to see their posts.

[0]: See; feeds.txt

-----------------------
Last Edited: 06/24/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genology in Desolation</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/artic.txt</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Genology in Desolation

Each specimen has been honed into the best iteration of their own local extrema, in both enivronment and genology.

There is also something alluring about the challenge of desolation; it is the truest form of examination -- the highest stakes of nature. To lose is to fail the process of evolution, to win is both the sucession of the future genome, and the justification for its current iteration. Elegantly, desolation is the levelest playing field of evolution; it is the most barren and honest plain (+/plane) on which to judge life.

Certainly, the overt complexity of more bountiful environments isn't a disqualification for their respective inhabitants; one can appreciate the lean, mean form of the cat as much as the streamlined elegance of the penguin. The deserts of the world are instead the most bare (barren) of all, and their inhabitants are nessecariliy the most effective, the most streamlined. Environmental complexity is much more naunced, and the number of inhabitants significantly reduced. This would lead one to beilive that this fascination is caused by the simplicity of evaluation -- it is much harder to comprehend why a jungle creature has evolved into its niche because of the complexity of its environment.

---------------------
Last Edited: 05/29/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Books should not be banned</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/books.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Books should not be banned
==========================

The state of Florida has engaged in overtly Orwellian legislation which has provided a legal framework for citizens to outright ban books in schools[0].
This is deeply troubling, but is unfortunately indicitive of a larger trend of proud stupidity.
      
Emotional thinking has become acceptable justifiaction for the parties of the United States. It justifies the loop of 'negative' voting[1], and provides the uneducated a base on which they feel comfortable. The uneducated will thus look to further reinforce their anchor of fear. The entirely draconian measure of banning books, which as excepted[2], is osetensibly done "for the children", is a means to an end. It substitutes reasonable discourse for emotional and personal opinion. The uneducated, having found a basis for their emotional opinions which they knowingly cannot justify sine rectus pretense, will attempt to restrict all other. Instead of having a constructive interpretation to challenges to their views, they emotionally react; drawing upon unchallengable pretense to justify their views; even substituting predicate logic as argument for pretense as argument. At which point, challenging their views is akin to challenging their pretenses, whether that be on religion, politics, or the nature of the universe. Only an one who is either an imbecile or malicous would do something so abhorrent.

[0]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230527021136/https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/republican-2024-hopeful-ron-desantis-is-blazing-a-trail-on-school-book-bans>
[1]: <https://www.notu.dev/txt/voting.txt>
[2]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230602025041/https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Think_of_the_children>

---------------------
Last Edited: 06/03/23 ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Codes of conduct are diametrically opposed to libre software</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/coc.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Codes of conduct are diametrically opposed to libre software
============================================================

Meritocracy is crucial when evaluating contributions to software, especially libre ac gratis software. The individual who has created the code matters less than the quality of the code. This is established as a best practice because it is the best practice. Some of the most technically correct FOSS organisations are founded on this principle[0][1]. It is idiotic to assign any value to code beyond its functionality, and by extension correctness.

Codes of conduct are generally bad; a key exception here is contribution guidelines, which serve to streamline the formatting of commits and bug reports. Codes of conduct remove the intrinsic impersonal evaluation of submitted code for niceties. One may compare it to a hamburger model of criticism[2]. In a domain such as software, it is incredibly important to have impersonal code, introducing codes of conduct for interpersonal conduct regarding such code muddies the waters. You either have entirely personal code, or impersonal code. Personal code introduces countless negative behaviors as many menial things become personal;
- Bug reports are now about the quality of YOUR personal code
- Necessary design changes are now an evaluation of YOUR design
- Troubleshooting is always the users fault, otherwise, it's YOUR fault

Not to needlessly simplify the matter; but in a healthy environment: your code isn't YOUR code. 

[0]: <https://suckless.org/philosophy/>
[1]: <https://www.openbsd.org/goals.html>
[2]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230329125440/https://hbr.org/2013/04/the-sandwich-approach-undermin>

-----------------------
Last Edited: 06/27/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nations as social contracts</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/contracts.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Nations as social contracts
===========================

Foreword: This is a consolidation of a series of converstations with a close friend, regarding the exact formulation of a nation in view of its participants. General statements, such as "come of age" are intentionally vauge, so as not to needlessly restrict the analysis via cultural differences between individual nations.

Nations can be formulated as social contracts implemented onto Natural Law. Inate citizenship of nations is given by birth within the nation's domain; otherwise ignoring explictly consensual citizenship. This is a function of the parents' endorsement of the nation's social contract, which can be refuted when the individual has come of age. The nation functions as a social contract wherin citizens affect its will via force, engage in it via their acceptance of the contract, and in some cases, govern it as a consequent of their contract. In this sense, the social contract is a voluntary extension of Natural Law.

Last Edited: 06/06/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Feeds</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/feeds.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Feeds
=====

Tweeter and other platforms that encourage short, hot takes have a debatable impact on the online ecosystem. That doesn't mean that they can't be done in a sane manner; running an RSS feed gives almost everything you could want.

> What about 'interaction'?
Narcissism aside, referential interaction can be done easily through links.

Curated feeds also make echo chambers[0] less potent; excluding external curation, generally you have to seek out new feeds.
Running a site is more complicated than running a feed; feeds are generally text based, which gives a nice layer of standardisation, while allowing individual sites to be unique in design.

One exception is the 'quality' of different RSS/Atom standards; I prefer 0.92; it removes the character restrictions and required sub-elements of 0.91 (otherwise I'd use 0.91). Character restriction of course removes nuance for brevity, and thus drives engagment through essentially rage-bait. Individual feeds, with no curation algorithm, have no such need. Individual posts are only as long as the author (or reader) intends.

RSS and other syndication feeds give power back to the reader; that is why walled gardens don't implement them overtly. You can, for instance, get the RSS feed of a youtube channel, but no where is that advertised; you have to go into the page source and do a text search. Odysee does implement this, even if they hide it in a drop-down menu (this should be next to the other buttons, perhaps next to subscribe?).

Individuals who typically use social media may be less likely to adopt a syndication feed. People with a small following are less likely to be 'discovered' if their horrible takes aren't being pushed by a curation algorithm. Good. Social media has been a imitation of the library of Babel; this is not something to replicate. You can take your infinite monkeys with you; I've already read Shakespeare.

[0]: "Echo chamber" has been diluted by online discourse. The term describes a curated feed which FURTHERS a descent into more extreme media.

-----------------------
Last Edited: 06/20/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>S/FTP -- The final frontier</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/ftp.txt</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[S/FTP -- The final frontier
=========================
S/FTP[0] is the best option for all file transfer operations. (anything but HTTP)

Generally, 'websites' should be done as a PASV (duh), anonymous or login-less read only FTP servers. The core benefit[1] of S/FTP is that configuration is fairly arbitrary, and so I provide the above only as a suggestion.

[0]: Note here that S/FTP refers to FTP and FTP via SSH.
[1]: Not including the brevity and simplicity of the protocol.
-----------------------
Last Edited: 06/21/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hacking: The penult step of simplicity</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/hack.txt</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Hacking: The penult step of simplicity
====================================

That sounds rather contradictory, doesn't it? Hacking, the act of cobbling together solutions from unintentional parts, would be the antithesis of simple, elegant solutions. A hacker can't help (or maybe he can) an inefficent part; the true art is the complete malleability of rigid parts.

Hacking is the much needed precusory work to a complete solution. Once you strip away the superfluous, you are able to truly assess the nature of the solution.
Generally one would;
1. Create a prototype
2. Bug test
3. Bug fix
4. goto #1

Hacking gets you a non-zero amount of #1; you're necessarily doing less work.

The astute observation is that hacking requires things to hack on, and that hacking is thus an intermediate step towards elegance. People break things all the time, hacking is just the profession. Hacking is the necessary coupling between different interations and intentions in programs. Good programs acknowledge this, and make the hackers' life easier (think the entirety of UNIX).


Post Script
===========
Some jumbled graphical representations

Typical coupling:
Prototype -> Hack -> Elegance
                  \____ Hack -> ...

Hacking is a iterative processs:
Hack -> ... -> Hack -> Elegance

One man's elegance is another man's prototype:
Prototype <-> Elegance
           |_____ Hack -> Elegance

-------------------
Last Edit: 06/09/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Magic ought to be free</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/magic.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Magic ought to be free
======================

Discussions of intellectual property[0] and the commons eventually all circle back to the question of freedom. It is unfortunate that the immediate assumption of freedom is as gratis, rather than libre. In certain cases, intellectual property can be free as in libre, but not as in gratis. One example being that of academic papers; generally when published, the reader must subscribe to the relevant journal to obtain the paper[1]. The reader is free to use and interpret that work in however perse sees fit, but initial access is not gratis.

This, we argue, should be the extent of strictly non-free intellectual property. At no point should intellectual property be non-libre. In the case of commercial, academic, or administrative works, access should be given freely and without restriction. The linchpin is the criteria for consideration; if an intellectual property is distributed for consumption, then it meets the criteria. This exempts personal work, including certain private research or unpublished works.

In the domain of software, this rule is crucial. The power wielded by humans via software and automation is magic incarnate. It is also a core part of our modern society; too much relies upon it not to be free. Banking, medicine, agriculture, airplanes, buses, trains, ships -- these are all dependent to some degree on software. We observe the recent debacle with John Deere v Farmers, where million dollar farm equipment locks its owner out via software, leading to a increase of jail-broken and pirated tractors[2]. We (the 'free' world) govern according to the ideals of a democratic republic; we ostensibly do not allow a centralised private power to rule our governance -- why would a domain so crucial to the same society be different?
 
[0]: For the sake of clarity, intellectual property is used, even though this document dictates an opposition to the fundamental concept.
[1]: Or reach out to the author directly (which almost always guarantees you a copy).
[2]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230331150227/https://tractorhacking.github.io/>

-----------------------
Last Edited: 07/02/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Markdown sucks</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/md.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Markdown sucks
==============

Once, I was smitten with markdown -- it was an enhanced plaintext format; what wasn't to love? Very soon I realised that intrinsically, there is no functional difference between markdown and plaintext, except for presentation. And like many of the visual protocols, it fell to bloated standards.

The issue is fundamentally one of control characters. Even the minimal amount of control characters intrinsically increases complexity; when you have an intermixed block of arbitrary text and control characters, the complexity is linear to the amount of control characters defined.

Markdown has set a precedent for acceptance; this results in ambiguous standards where nearly all non-alphanumeric characters represent some portion of some control sequence. It is a significant pain to NOT accidentally transcribe a control character.

At the risk of slightly lackluster presentation (the horror), plaintext is exactly what you intend it to be. With the addition of unicode, it's even possible to make plaintext flashy, but I've found that plain old ASCII is enough for me.

Post Script
===========
> John Gruber’s canonical description of Markdown’s syntax does not specify the syntax unambiguously. [0]
> Because there is no unambiguous spec, implementations have diverged considerably over the last 10 years. As a result, users are often surprised to find that a document that renders one way on one system (say, a GitHub wiki) renders differently on another (say, converting to docbook using Pandoc). To make matters worse, because nothing in Markdown counts as a “syntax error,” the divergence often isn’t discovered right away. [0]

The grand experiment of intrepting plaintext as control sequences has resulted in ... ambiguity. Could anyone have forseen this?

[0]: <https://web.archive.org/web/20230603082515/https://commonmark.org/>

---------------------
Last Edited: 06/06/23]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nintendo -- Art and Morals</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/nintendo.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Nintendo -- Art and Morals
==========================

Nintendo is the the forbidden fruit of art. A company which has a lengthily record of malignant intent directly towards its consumers, but also produces some of the most beautiful and well regarded games of the modern era. The impact of intention begetting knowledge is certainly an old question; it is literally biblical.

In the Book of Genesis, God forbids Adam and Eve from eating the apple from the Tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil -- they do not comply, and under the reasonable presumption of Jehovah, that they will eat next from the Tree of Life, they are expelled. This fork of decision; to eat or not to eat, forms the basis of the two traditions -- (religious) morality, and that of humanism. Underlying both are common morals; as Kurtz writes in Toward A New Enlightenment, "[the morals] express the elementary virtues of courtesy, politeness, and empathy so essential for living together; indeed, they are the very basis of civilized life itself" (Kurtz, 26). The former is tradition judged by wisdom; intelligence handed down from eons of human thought. The latter is the adaptation of the former to the present and future. Effective ethics is necessarily an amalgamation of the two.

The story of the Trees of Knowledge and Life is binary. If Adam and Eve were not to eat from the tree, how could they know Good and Evil? How could they know God is Good? The story of the Trees of Knowledge and Life gives the responsibility for evaluation of the metaphysical to humanity. As Oderberg describes in The Metaphysics of Good and Evil, "Our world is essentially and fundamentally a world of act and potency" (Oderberg, 42). Upon this plane, the recursive states of potency; that which could be, and of act; that which is -- are the only definitions axiomatic to Good and Evil. Things are defined intrinsically; "[the] essence of an existing object is itself an actuality" (Oderberg, 48). Things only must act in a way proper to their nature, and in a way which is not opposite to that nature. Good is the default state of things. So how to evaluate a thing which is Good according to its nature, but whose accordance is in opposition to its potential?

The games produced by Nintendo are works of art -- devoid of anything but craftsmanship and appreciation for true beauty. It is the reputation on which all existing Nintendo games have been staked upon. This is the same reputation which has a dual history of vicious prosecution of virtuous fan content and their creators (almost entirely produced as a result of absence of an official entity). How cruel is fate; that Nintendo's games Good, and Nintendo Evil? Now, many are faced with a choice -- which tradition to adopt. I for one, forsake the Trees of Knowledge and Life; how could beauty exist as the product of Evil, if it were truly beauty?

Citations:
Kurtz, Paul. Toward A New Enlightenment, 1994. ISBN: 9781351294409.
Oderberg, S. David. The Metaphysics of Good and Evil, 2020. ISBN: 9780367408640.

Post Script:
I'd HIGHLY recommend a full read of Oderberg's work -- it is incredibly lucid, and of course valuable.

Last Edited:
07/18/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Day of Rest</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/rest.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[A Day of Rest

You need not be religious to subscribe to a day of rest. A whole day of rest is incredibly beneficial in the typical 5-6 day workweek.
- A whole day of rest is concentrated, and thus is more effective than incremental periods of rest during work days.
- A consistent whole day of rest builds more typical work patterns.

Last Edited: 07/09/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Temperature and value</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/temp.txt</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Temperature and value
========================

Theory: We rank value by relevance to our base temperature.

Valuable:
- Cool
- Chill
- Cold
- Hot
- Fire

Mediocre:
- Lukewarm
- Mid
- Warm

On further reflection, this is mostly an intrinsic property of ranking on a gradient.

----------------------
Last Edited 06/27/2023]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Voting is important; not to 'win', but rather for the participation in the process.</title>
<link>https://www.notu.dev/txt/voting.txt</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Voting is important; not to 'win', but rather for the participation in the process.
===================================================================================

Voting as honest participation in the process is 'positive' voting; that is, voting in favor of legistlation that you holistically agree with.
Voting to stop the 'other side' from success is 'negative' voting; this generally includes intentionally deadlocking legislation or candidacy for office.</p>
      
Majoritarian electoral systems corrupt the meaning of voting through 2 major processes:
1. The consolidation of voters
2. The reinforcement of 'negative' voting

These form a series of run-off processes, which serve to further reinforce the two major processes.
In no particular order: 
  a. The precipitation of policy and identity ambiguity
  b. Legislative deadlock in systems with delayed terms
  c. The loss of the moderates
  d. The normalisation of advocacy for extreme policy

Big parties formed via the consolidation of voters through 'negative' voting are incentivised to cater to the extremes of their general alignment. These extreme voters have no qualms about voting 'positively'; consequently, their voting patterns inspire the opposing moderates to vote 'negatively'. They thus form the crucial margin for large parties; they serve to keep the moderates in check, while providing the literal margin for election. Extreme policy is accordingly promoted to attract these extreme voters, and the moderates are relegated to an infinite loop of 'negative' voting.

There will be growing pains as the moderates play an increasingly high-stakes game of chicken, but the only intra-process reform possible is enacted through voting 'positively'.

-------------------
Last Edit: 05/28/23 ]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>
